allevents.in 2018-10-11

# Privacy Policy

## Introduction

This policy sets out how we collect, process and hold your data if you visit our website or otherwise provide personal data to us. We are AllEvents.in of AllEvents Informations Pvt. Ltd. 

This policy affects your legal rights and obligations so please read it carefully. If you have any questions, please contact us at [privacy@allevents.in](mailto:privacy@allevents.in)

## Information we collect, store and process

###  General Information

When you visit, interact or use our website, we collect general data and may as well collect personal data. General Data usually includes cookies that is recorded automatically when you first visit the website, to give you a better experience when you revisit our website. Personal Data include your name, your contact information and few other personal details as permitted by you. 

We collect, process, store and use personal data when you authorize us to see your personal details after you login on our platform directly or through third party login system. 

We store your personal information for a limited time period when you book a ticket to an event. 

You do not need to provide us with any personal information to view our website. However, we may still collect the information set under the cookie statement section of this policy, 'Data we automatically collect' section of this policy and marketing communications in accordance with the 'Marketing Communications' section of this policy. When you contact us by email or post, we may keep a record of the correspondence and we may also record any telephone call we have with you. 

###  **Users**

General information is automatically recorded from all the users. The data which is automatically collected includes the technical data that is sent to us from the computer, mobile device and browser through which users access our website or it's services. Users action on our website, information on how users came to our website and data collected through Cookies, Pixel Code and other similar technologies are all included in the automatic general information collection. 

###  **Event Organizers**

If you are an event organizer, we collect additional necessary data from your end. 

Additional Data such as your name, your organization name, your event details and contact information is recorded with us. This information is also visible to people who are interested in your event or purchase tickets to your events. 

When an organizer activates ticketing on our platform, we may also collect your financial information from you, for example your bank account information or your paypal account information or any third party payment account information to transfer the ticket amount or resolve issues related to payment. We only use your financial data as far as transfer of funds is required, be it for using our promotion services or for ticketing and box office operations. We never store or sell your financial data to anyone. You have the right to delete your organizer account as and when you require, unless in case a payment issue or a fraudulent matter appears. 

###  **Consumers/Event Attendees/Subscribers**

If you are a consumer or an event attendee or someone who uses AllEvents.in to discover events and get tailored event recommendations or if you login on our website, we collect additional data from your end such as your name and contact information. This additional data is mostly used for our own purposes. However, when you register for an event through AllEvents.in or buy tickets for paid events, we collect that data on behalf of the event organizer and do not store it for more than 6 months. The period of 6 months is taken into consideration to solve payment or registration related disputes if it happens. As a consumer, when you fill an event inquiry form or enter a coupon code or buy tickets or contact the organizer through our system, your contact details are shared with the organizer to help organizer identify you and reach you for any communication related to that event or for their upcoming events. When you interact with organizers/users through our chat feature or through our chat plugin on any website, you will be introduced to organizer with your email id to better connect with you and provide you with the service/support that you were expecting from them. 

If you are receiving event invitations emails for a particular event using our email invitation platform from an organizer, we will notify you in the email that it is being sent by the organizer using our service and we do not store that data in our system. You can at any point unsubscribe directly from such mails or contact the organizer directly to delete your data. If you contact us, we may remove or update your information within a reasonable time. 

## **Data we automatically collect**

When you visit our website, login or buy tickets from our website, we, or third parties on our behalf, automatically collect and store information about your device and your activities. This information could include (a) your computer or other device's unique ID number; (b) technical information about your device such as type of device, web browser or operating system; (c) your preferences and settings such as time zone and language; and (d) statistical data about your browsing actions and patterns. We collect this information using cookies in accordance with the Cookie section of this policy and we use the information we collect on an anonymous basis to improve our events and events related services we provide, and for analytical and research purposes. 

We also allow advertisers and advertising networks to collect information about your computer or mobile device, activities, and geographic location to enable them to display targeted ads to you and provide us with anonymous information about our users' behaviour. This takes place through the use of cookies in accordance with the Cookie section of this policy. 

## **Event Updates and Other Electronic Communication**

It is necessary for our legitimate interests to use your contact information and interests to send you updates and other communications, which may include newsletters, blog posts, surveys, case studies, our products or services, offers, general queries, feedback and information about new events. 

You can choose to no longer receive particular or any type of communication by contacting us at privacy@allevents.in or clicking "Unsubscribe" from an email. If you do unsubscribe to any particular communication, it may take up to 5 business days for your new preferences to take effect. We shall therefore retain your personal data in our records for business purposes until you notify us that you no longer wish to receive emails from us. Please note that unsubscribing from a particular communication email does not mean unsubscribing from all the emails. You can choose which emails you would like to receive by reviewing your settings. To do so, login to your account on AllEvents.in, and from the top bar, near your profile thumbnail, you will see a drop down, hovering on that dropdown you will be able to see the settings option and enable/disable any particular type of communication or you can simply [click here ](https://allevents.in/profile/settings.php)to review your settings. At any point you can change settings for the type of communication you want or do not want to receive. 

Unsubscribing from marketing or service related communication emails does not mean that you may not receive weekly newsletter or event updates for which you opted in or based on the organizer profiles or city you follow or showed your interest at the time of signing up on AllEvents.in. If you never want to receive any emails from us or want to delete your preferences & profile, you can raise your concern on [privacy@allevents.in](mailto:privacy@allevents.in). 

## **Organizer Initiated Communications**

We provide email tools to organizers through which they can send electronic communication to those who are on their email subscription lists, including consumers who may have registered for their upcoming and past events. AllEvents.in provides platform for event organizers to send event invitations to their customers. While these electronic communications are sent using our system, we are not responsible for it's message or inclusions. Any information, business or advertising communications sent from it, is sole responsibility of the event organizer. Event Organizers must obtain their email list in a legit way. Any dispute with the data of Organizer Initiated Communication shall be resolved by the Event Organizer. 

The recipients can choose to "opt out" of electronic communications from a particular event organizer through the "Unsubscribe" link at the end of each of these emails. 

## **Lawful processing of your personal data**

We will use your data in order to comply with our contractual obligation to supply to you the tickets to an event that you have booked, including to contact you with any information relating to the event, to deliver the event to you in accordance with any requests you make and that we agree to, and to deal with any questions, comments or complaints you have in relation to the event. 

We may also use your personal data for our legitimate interests, including dealing with any customer services you require, enforcing the terms of any other agreement between us, for regulatory and legal purposes (for example anti-money laundering), for audit purposes and to contact you about changes to this policy. 

## **Who do we share your data with?**

We may share your data with any service providers, subcontractors and agents that we may appoint to perform functions on our behalf and in accordance with our instructions, including payment providers, event organizers, email communication providers, IT service providers, partner platforms, accountants, auditors and lawyers. 

Under certain circumstances we may have to disclose your personal data under applicable laws and/or regulations, for example, as part of anti-money laundering processes or protect a third party's rights, property, or safety. 

We may also share your personal data in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of assets, consolidation or restructuring, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by or into another company. 

## **Where we hold and process your personal data**

Some or all of your personal data may be stored or transferred outside of the European Union (the EU) for any reason, including for example, if our email server is located in a country outside the EU or if any of our service providers or their servers are based outside of the EU. We shall only transfer your personal data to organisations that have provided adequate safeguards in respect of your personal data and are GDPR Compliant. 

## **Retention**

If you receive communication from us, we shall retain your data until you opt out of receiving such communications. If you register with us, we shall retain your data until you close your account. You can delete your data or your account by contacting us on privacy@allevents.in 

However, we may hold your data for an extra period as is allowed or required under applicable laws. Your data after complete deletion might still be available on backup for even a longer period of time for reasons persistence to legal, tax and lawful business purposes. 

If you have otherwise booked a ticket with us or contacted us with a question or comment, we shall retain your personal information for at least 6 months following such contact to respond to any further queries you might have. 

When an individual books a ticket for an event, their personal data like name, email id and ticket information is shared with the event organizer for coordinating check-ins during the event. If by any means, an event organizers plans to use that information for their own purpose, it is on the sole discretion of the event organizer. All Events or its partner websites is not responsible for how organizers use that data as we never store data collected during the ticket buying process for more than 6 months. The period of 6 months is considered in case if there is any payment dispute after the event between the event organizer and ticket buyer or event organizer and payment gateway or ticket buyer and payment gateway. 

## **Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred (through your browser) from a website to the hard drive of your computer. The cookie identifies your browser but will not let a website know any personal data about you, such as your name and/or address. These files are then used by websites to identify when users revisit that website. 

Our website uses cookies so that we can recognise you when you return and personalise your settings and preferences. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can change your browser settings either to notify you when you have received a cookie, or to refuse to accept cookies. Please note that we may not be able to remember your choices or operate efficiently or give you personalized experience if you refuse to accept cookies. 

We also use Google Analytics to monitor how our website is used. Google Analytics collects information anonymously and generates reports detailing information such as the number of visits to the event ticket shop, where visitors generally came from, how long they stayed on the event ticket shop, and which pages they visited. Google Analytics places several persistent cookies on your computer's hard drive. These do not collect any personal data. If you do not agree to this you can disable persistent cookies in your browser. This will prevent Google Analytics from logging your visits. 

We also use Social Networking Cookies or tracking pixels on our event pages, which remembers your interest for a particular event or piece of information available on our and partner websites. This is done to show you relevant ads on the social networking sites. For more information about the pixel tracking you can checkout [Facebook Data Policy](https://www.facebook.com/policies/cookies/) and [Smartlook](https://www.smartlook.com/help/privacy-statement/). 

To support our business we also allow third party advertisements on our website. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our website, which will also send these advertisers your automatically collected information such as IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site when you interact or even see their advertisement on our site. For more details regarding how we third party vendors, including google manages data in its ads products, please check the [partner-sites policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites) as provided by Google. 

## **Security**

We shall process your data in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the data, including protection against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage, using appropriate technical or organisational measures. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions are encrypted using SSL technology. 

Where we have given, or you have chosen a password, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential.However, you acknowledge that no system can be completely secure. Therefore, although we take these steps to secure your data, we do not promise that your data will always remain completely secure. 

## **Your rights**

You have the right to obtain from us a copy of the personal data that we hold for you, and to require us to correct errors in that data if it is inaccurate or incomplete. You also have the right at any time to require that we delete your personal data,object to profiling and unsubscribe from marketing communications. To exercise these rights, or any other rights you may have under applicable laws, please contact us at [privacy@allevents.in.](mailto:privacy@allevents.in)

Please note, we reserve the right to charge an administrative fee if your request is manifestly unfounded or excessive. 

If you have any complaints in relation to this policy or otherwise in relation to our processing of your data, please get in touch with us at [privacy@allevents.in](mailto:contact@allevents.in), so we can resolve your complaint. If you are not satisfied with our attempt to resolve your privacy related complaints, you may contact the relevant data protection authority. 

Our website pages may contain links to other sites of interest. Once you have used these links to leave our platform, you should note that we do not have any control over that other site. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this policy. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy policy applicable to the site in question. 

## **API & Plugins Use**

Allevents.in aggregates public events from multiple third party providers from their APIs. We take request from APIs only for the public events and not private events. In cases, where a user or an event organizer or any individual might want to report an event, they can do so through the event page or by contacting us at [privacy@allevents.in](mailto:privacy@allevents.in)

We also provide APIs and Event Plugins to third party or partner websites which implies that when an individual creates an event on allevents.in, it may be used by third party or partner websites to display your events for a greater reach. 

## **Facebook, Gmail and Other Third Party Integrations**

You can login to allevents using your Facebook or Gmail Accounts, in which case, we may collect, store and use information connected with the third party account with your permission. 

All the third party integrations and the company or organisation names mentioned in this policy have their own copyright/wordmark, trademark, terms, security and privacy policy which can be found on their own website. 

## **Changes of this privacy statement**

We may change the terms of this policy from time to time. You are responsible for regularly reviewing this policy so that you are aware of any changes to it. If you continue to use our website after the time we state the changes will take effect, you will have accepted the changes.
